Guide to the Dwight Macdonald Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1864, 1888, 1912-1978; Series I; 23 linear feet (62 boxes)
  - General
    - Kryss, Thomas L.
      See: Series II, Subject File, James Russell Lowell box 29, folder 752
    - Kubrick, Stanley, 1959-1962 (Box 26, Folder 693)
    - Kuenning, William H., 1946 (Box 26, Folder 694)
    - Kuerti, Anton
    - Kultura, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 695)
    - Kupcinet, Iru, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 696)
    - La (Box 26, Folder 697)
    - Labadie, Laurance, 1945-1949, 1952 (Box 26, Folder 698)
    - Labor Action, 1942, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 699)
    - Labor Feature Syndicate (Box 26, Folder 699)
      See box 50, folder 1213
    - LaFollette, Suzanne
      See: box 34, folder 859 box 36, folder 903
    - Lafollette, Robert M., Jr., 1947 (Box 26, Folder 700)
    - [Lamb, Robert K.?], 1925-[1927?]-1928 (Box 27, Folder 701)
    - Lanes, Jerrold, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 702)
    - Larrabee, Eric, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 703)
    - Lasch, Christopher, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 704)
    - Lash, Joseph P., [1949?] (Box 27, Folder 705)
    - Lasky, Melvin J.,(*), [1939?], 1940, 1943-1949, 1953-1954, 1956-1960, 1963-1967 (Box 27, Folder 706-707)
      See also: box 15, folder 375 box 27, folder 715 box 50, folder 1205 box 48, folder 1171
    - Laucks, Irving, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 708)
    - [Laufer, Max?], 1949 (Box 27, Folder 709)
    - Laughlin, James, 1940, [1943?]-1944, 1948, 1952-1955 (Box 27, Folder 710)
    - Laurat, Lucien, 1945-1947 (Box 27, Folder 711)
    - Lauter, Paul, 1969, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 712)
    - Malgrange, Léon, 1946-1949 (Box 27, Folder 713)
    - Lazere, Donald, 1956, 1958, 1963, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 714)
    - Le (Box 27, Folder 715)
    - League for Cultural Freedom and Socialism (Box 27, Folder 715)
    - "Daladier Cablegram," "International Federation of Independent Revolutionary Art," and miscellaneous, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 716)
    - "Statement to American Writers and Artiste", 1939 (Box 27, Folder 717-718)
      See also: box 21, folder 555 box 36, folder 912 box 43, folder 1055 box 43, folder 1060 box 47, folder 1143 box 60, folder 1418
    - "War is the Issue", 1939 (Box 27, Folder 719)
    - League for Cultural Freedom and Socialism (Box 27, Folder 719)
      See also: box 116, folder 585
    - League for Freedom
      See: box 25, folder 657
    - League for Industrial Democracy, 1940, 1960, 1964, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 720)
    - League for Mutual Aid
      See: box 9, folder 195 box 45, folder 1113
    - League of American Writers, New York chapter
      See: box 101, folder 482
    - Lee, Eric, 1947-1949, 1951-1952 (Box 28, Folder 721)
    - Lee, Marshall, 1968-1970, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 722)
    - LEFT
      See: box 15, folder 384
    - Legman, Gershon, 1946, 1966-1967, undated (Box 28, Folder 723)
    - Lehfeldt, Hans, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 724)
    - Lennhoff, Herbert, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 725)
    - Leonard, Thomas J., 1947 (Box 28, Folder 726)
    - Lerner, Abba P., 1945, 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 727)
    - Lerner, Daniel(*), 1953-1956, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 728)
    - Lerner, Max, 1952, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 729)
    - Lettvin, Jerome, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 730)
    - Leuchtenburg, William E., 1948 (Box 28, Folder 731)
    - Levi, Albert William, 1944-1946 (Box 28, Folder 732)
    - Levi, Mario, 1947, 1958-1959 (Box 28, Folder 733)
    - Levine, Jack, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 734)
    - Levy, Leonard, 1944-[1945?] (Box 28, Folder 735)
    - Lewis, Richard W.B., 1970 (Box 28, Folder 736)
    - Lewis, Wyndham, 1944, 1947, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 737)
      See also: box 16, folder 403 box 43, folder 1069
    - Li - Lz (Box 28, Folder 738)
    - Lichtenstein, Stanley, 1944, 1946, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 739)
    - Life, 1937, 1948, 1958, 1961, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 740)
    - Lifton, Robert Jay, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 741)
    - Limon, Didier L., [1947?] (Box 28, Folder 742)
    - J.B. Lippincott Company, 1954, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 743)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 744)
    - Lipset, Seymour Martin, 1945, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 745)
    - List, R. Kurt, [1943?]-1944 (Box 28, Folder 746)
    - Little, Brown & Company, 1937, 1961-1962 (Box 28, Folder 747)
    - Logue, Christopher, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 748)
      See also: box 21, folder 531 box 23, folder 581 box 35, folder 879
    - London School of Economics
      See: box 6, folder 101
    - Long, Breckenridge
      See: box 60, folder 1418
    - Longanesi & C., 1960 (Box 28, Folder 749)
    - Longstaff, Stephan A., 1972, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 750)
    - Losey, Joseph, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 751)
    - Louzon, Robert, 1947-1948 (Box 29, Folder 752)
    - Lowell, Amy
      See: box 16, folder 403
    - Lowell (James R.) Legal Defense Committee
      See: box 117, folder 590
    - Lowell, Robert, 1948, 1965, 1967-1969 (Box 29, Folder 753)
    - Lowenstein, Allard K., 1968, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 754)
    - Lowenthal, Leo, 1960, 1963, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 755)
    - Lowenthal, Marjorie Fiske (Mrs. Leo), 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 755)
    - Luce, Henry III, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 756)
    - Luce, Henry R., 1931, 1934, 1936 (Box 29, Folder 757)
    - Lukacs, Helen (Mrs. John), 1961-1962, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 758)
    - Lukacs, John A.,(*), [1940s?], 1953-1973, 1977, undated (Box 30, Folder 759-764)
    - Lukacs, Paul (son of John), 1962, undated (Box 30, Folder 765)
    - Lumet, Sidney, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 766)
      See also: box 99, folder 415
    - Lundberg, Ferdinand, 1939, 1948, undated (Box 30, Folder 767)
      See also: box 27, folder 715 box 34, folder 859
    - Lynd, Robert S., 1944-[1945?] (Box 30, Folder 768)
    - Lynd, Staughton, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 769)
    - Lynes, Russell, 1952, 1954-1955, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 770)
    - Lynn, Conrad, 1943-1948 (Box 30, Folder 771)
      See also: box 117, folder 599
    - Lynn, Winfred, 1942-1943 (Box 30, Folder 771)
    - Lynn Committee to Abolish Segregation in the Armed Forces(*), 1943-1945 (Box 30, Folder 772)
      See also: box 25, folder 664 box 36, folder 904 box 55, folder 340 box 118, folder 599
    - Lyons, Eugene, 1940, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 773)
      See also: box 34, folder 859 box 9, folder 212
    - Mac (Box 31, Folder 774)
    - McCandless, John H., 1946-1947 (Box 31, Folder 775)
    - McCarran, Pat, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 776)
    - McCarthy, Albert J., 1945-1947, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 777)
    - McCarthy (Eugene) Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 778)
      See also: box 55, folder 340
    - McCarthy, Mary(*), [1945?]-1953, 1955-[1956?]-1957, 1959, 1961-1967, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 779-780)
      See also: box 9, folder 194 box 9, folder 211 box 48, folder 1171 box 56, folder 1361 box 60, folder 1401 box 60, folder 1412
    - McCloskey, Burr, 1943 (Box 31, Folder 781)
    - McDonald, Shannon, 1968, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 782-783)
    - McDowell, David, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 784)
    - Macedonia Cooperative Community
      See: box 60, folder 1414
    - McGovern (George) Presidential Campaign, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 785)
    - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 786)
    - Mclnerny, Kathleen, 1937-1938 (Box 31, Folder 787)
    - McKeever, Porter, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 788)
    - McKelway, St. Clair, 1936, 1960, 1962, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 789)
    - Mackenzie, Cameron, 1937 (Box 31, Folder 790)
    - McKenzie, Dorothy, 1945-1946, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 791)
    - MacLean, Helene, 1940-1941, 1955, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 792)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1937, 1945, undated (Box 31, Folder 793)
    - Macklin, F. Anthony(*), 1964-1969, 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 794)
    - MacLow, Jackson, 1944-1946 (Box 31, Folder 795)
      See also: box 78, folder 145
    - McLuhan, Marshall, 1946, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 796)
    - The Macmillan Company(*), 1948, 1960-1962, 1964, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 797)
    - McNamara, Robert S.
      See: box 119, folder 604
    - McNatt, Isaac G., 1944, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 798)
    - McPhee, John, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 799)
    - McQuade, Walter, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 800)
    - Macrorie, Ken, 1952 (Box 32, Folder 801)
    - McWilliams, Carey
      See: box 35, folder 902 box 55, folder 340
    - Mad - Mars (Box 32, Folder 802)
    - Magriel, Paul D., 1959, 1965, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 803)
    - Mailer, Norman (includes copy of The Time of Her Time ) (*), (1944-1949?], 1952, 1956-[1960?], 1964, 1967-1968, 1970, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 804)
      See also: box 15, folder 379 box 16, folder 418 box 23, folder 601 box 48, folder 1171 box 88, folder 317
    - Malaquais, Galy (Mrs. Jean), 1947 (Box 32, Folder 805)
    - Malaquais, Jean(*), 1943-1947, 1949, 1963-1964 (Box 32, Folder 805)
    - Malaquais-Deberdt, Elizabeth (Mrs. Jean Malaquais), 1963 (Box 32, Folder 805)
    - Moulin, Léo, undated (Box 32, Folder 806)
    - Malin, Patrick Murphy
      See: box 5, folder 73
    - Man, Albon, 1946-1948, 1950, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 807)
    - Man, Paul de, 1949 (Box 33, Folder 808)
    - Manas
    - Manchester, William, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 809)
    - Mangan, Sherry, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 810)
    - Manheim, Mary (Mrs. Ralph)(*), 1943-1949, [1953?], 1968, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 811)
    - Manheim, Ralph(*), 1944, 1946-1950, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 812)
    - Mankiewicz, Frank, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 813)
    - Manly, Basil
      See: box 129-132, folder 708-729
    - Mann, Georg, 1945-1947 (Box 33, Folder 814)
    - Mann, Thomas
    - Manning, Robert
      See: box 6, folder 104
    - Marc, Alexandre, 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 815)
    - March on Washington Movement
      See: box 119, folder 606
    - Marchant, Will
      See: box 49, folder 1185
    - Marcuse, Herbert
    - Markel, Lester, 1963, 1972, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 816)
    - Markfield, Wallace, 1947, 1951 (Box 33, Folder 817)
    - Marsh, Corinna, 1945, 1947, 1949 (Box 33, Folder 818)
    - Marshall, Lenore G., 1950 (Box 33, Folder 819)
      See also: box 9, folder 211 box 137, folder 776
    - Marshall, Margaret, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 820)
    - Marshall, T.H.
    - Marshall, Thurgood, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 821)
    - Mart - May (Box 33, Folder 822)
    - Martin, David
      See: box 24, folder 612
    - The Marxian Way
      See: box 23, folder 592
    - Mascaró, Juan, 1961 (Box 33, Folder 823)
    - Masefield, John, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 824)
    - Masters, Dexter, 1966, 1968, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 825)
    - Matson, Norman, 1947-[1949?], 1952-1953 (Box 33, Folder 826)
    - Mattheissen, F.O., undated (Box 33, Folder 827)
    - Mattick, Paul(*), 1941, 1943-[1945?]-1949 (Box 33, Folder 828)
    - Maxwell, William, 1957, 1960, 1962, 1971, undated (Box 33, Folder 829)
    - Mayo, Elton, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 830)
    - Mayo, Robert D., 1968 (Box 33, Folder 831)
    - Me (Box 33, Folder 832)
    - Mead, Herbert
    - Mears, Helen(*), 1944-1949, 1951, 1953-1954, undated (Box 33, Folder 833)
    - Measure, 1948-1950 (Box 33, Folder 834)
    - Mehta, Ved(*), 1959-[1961?]-1963, 1965, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 835)
    - Melman, Seymour, 1946, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 836)
    - Menninger, Karl, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 837)
    - Meredith, Scott, 1975-1977 (Box 33, Folder 838)
    - Meridian Books, Inc., 1958-1960 (Box 33, Folder 839)
    - Merleau-Ponty, Maurice, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 840)
    - Meyer, Ernest L.
      See: box 36, folder 903
    - Meyer, Frank S., 1956, 1963-1964 (Box 34, Folder 841)
    - Meyer, Howard N.
      See: box 129, folder 702
    - Meyer, Karl E., 1962, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 842)
    - Mi (Box 34, Folder 843)
    - Michigan Commonwealth Federation, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 844)
    - Midstream, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 845)
    - Milano, Paolo, 1948, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 846)
    - Milgram, Morris, 1946, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 847)
    - Miller, Arthur, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 848)
      See also: box 16, folder 400
    - Miller, Barry(*), 1947-1948, 1953-1954 (Box 34, Folder 849)
      See also: box 16, folder 394 box 23, folder 595
    - Miller, Durham, 1963 (Box 34, Folder 850)
    - Miller, Henry, 1945 (Box 34, Folder 851)
    - Miller, Jonathan, 1962-1964 (Box 34, Folder 852)
    - Miller, Judy(*), 1948-1949 (Box 34, Folder 853)
    - Miller, William R., 1952, 1954 (Box 34, Folder 854)
    - Mills, C. Wright(*), 1942-1950, 1952, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 855)
      See also: box 52, folder 1262
    - Milosz, Czeslaw, 1953, 1958-1959, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 856)
    - Mini, Norman, 1943, 1947, undated (Box 34, Folder 857)
    - Minow, Newton N., 1962 (Box 34, Folder 858)
    - "Mission to Moscow", 1943 (Box 34, Folder 859)
      See also: box 19, folder 470 box 42, folder 1034 box 125, folder 667
    - Mississippi Newsletter, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 860)
    - Mitarachi, Paul J., 1958 (Box 34, Folder 861)
    - Mitchell, Broadus, 1946-1947 (Box 34, Folder 862)
    - Mizener, Arthur, 1942, 1949 (Box 34, Folder 863)
    - Moc - Mot (Box 34, Folder 864)
    - The Moderator, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 865)
    - Modern Books
      See: box 26, folder 685
    - Modern Occasions
      See: box 42, folder 1030
    - Modern Review
      See: box 11, folder 254 box 12, folder 288
    - Moholy-Nagy, L.
      See: box 152, folder 12
    - Moholy-Nagy, Sibyl, 1952, 1954, 1958, 1960-1963, 1965-1971 (Box 34, Folder 866)
    - Monocle, 1963-1965, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 867)
    - Montagu, Ashley, 1967-1969 (Box 34, Folder 868)
    - Monthly Review, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 869)
    - Moreau, Jacques, 1947-1949 (Box 34, Folder 870)
    - Morgan, Al, 1962-1963 (Box 34, Folder 871)
    - Morgenbesser, Sidney, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 872)
    - Morgenthau, Henry
    - Morin, Alexander J., 1958 (Box 34, Folder 873)
    - Morris, George L.K., 1927-[1931-1932?]-1936 (Box 35, Folder 874)
    - Morris, George L.K.(*), 1938-[1939?]-1940-[1941-1942?]-1943, 1945-1947, [1956-1957?] 1966, 1971, undated (Box 35, Folder 875)
    - Morris, Suzy (Mrs. George L.K.), 1937, 1953, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 876)
    - Morris, William
      See: box 6, folder 78 box 21, folder 530
    - Morrow, Felix, 1938, 1940, 1948, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 877)
    - William Morrow & Company, Inc., 1936, 1947, 1963-1964 (Box 35, Folder 878)
    - Morse, Wayne
    - Moss, Howard, 1963 (Box 35, Folder 879)
    - Most, Mel, 1950, 1963, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 880)
    - Mou - My (Box 35, Folder 881)
    - Péret, Benjamin, 1947-1948 (Box 35, Folder 882)
    - Mounier, Emmanuel, 1946-1948 (Box 35, Folder 883)
    - Mowry, George, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 884)
    - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, 1958, 1964 (Box 35, Folder 885)
    - Muggeridge, Malcolm, 1962, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 886)
    - Mulfinger, Gus, 1961-1963 (Box 35, Folder 887)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1965, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 888)
      See also: box 48, folder 1171 box 55, folder 340
    - Munroe, Vernon, Jr., 1925-[1926?], 1960 (Box 35, Folder 889)
    - Munson, Gorham B., 1947 (Box 35, Folder 890)
    - Murphy, Gardner, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 891)
    - Muste, A.J.(*), 1944, 1946-1949, 1951, [1952?], 1954 (Box 35, Folder 892)
    - Muste, A.J.(*), 1955, 1964-1966, undated (Box 35, Folder 893)
      See also: box 9, folder 211 box 125, folder 670
    - Myers, E. Pauline(*)
    - Myers, John, 1945 (Box 35, Folder 894)
    - The Mysterious East, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 895)
    - Na (Box 35, Folder 896)
    - Nabokov, Nicolas, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 897)
    - Nabokov, Peter, 1964 (Box 35, Folder 898)
    - Nabokov, Vladimir, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 899)
      See also: box 88, folder 316
    - Naftalin, Arthur, 1948-1950, 1953 (Box 35, Folder 900)
    - Nasser, Gamal Abdel, 1957 (Box 35, Folder 901)
    - The Nation, 1937-1939, 1942-1943, 1946, 1949, 1958, 1961-1963, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 902)
      See also: box 15, folder 373 box 16, folder 394 box 24, folder 625 box 26, folder 670 box 36, folder 920
    - "The Nation Letter" (*), 1938 (Box 36, Folder 903)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 904)
    - National Caucus of Labor Committees, 1971-1972 (Box 36, Folder 905)
    - National Committee for a Free Europe, 1951 (Box 36, Folder 906)
    - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy, Inc., 1958, 1960, 1965, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 907)
    - National Committee on Conscientous Objectors
      See: box 22, folder 567
    - National Conference for New Politics
      See: box 38, folder 960 box 125-126, folder 672-675
    - National Council Against Conscription, 1947 (Box 36, Folder 908)
    - The National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 36, Folder 909)
    - National Lawyers Guild, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 910)
    - National Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam
      See: box 13, folder 322
    - National Psychological Institute
      See: box 6, folder 90
    - National Sharecroppers Fund, Inc., 1948 (Box 36, Folder 911)
    - Naville, Pierre, [1930s?], 1945, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 912)
    - Ne - Nu (Box 36, Folder 913)
    - Nebolsine, Arcadi, 1969, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 914)
    - Nelson, Benjamin N.(*), 1945-1951, 1955, 1961, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 915)
    - Nelson, Gaylord, 1964 (Box 36, Folder 916)
    - Neville, Helen, 1953, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 917)
    - New Candidate Campaign Committee., 1972 (Box 36, Folder 918)
    - The New Journal, 1968 (Box 36, Folder 919)
    - The New Leader, 1939, 1946-1947, 1949-[1952?]-1954, 1959, 1962-1965, 1973, undated (Box 36, Folder 920)
    - New Letters, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 921)
    - New Politics, 1967, 1969, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 922)
    - The New Republic, 1937, 1944, 1948, 1956, 1958-1959, 1961-1962, 1964, 1966, 1973, undated (Box 36, Folder 923)
      See also: box 20, folder 516 box 21, folder 535 box 21, folder 544 box 43, folder 1055 box 7272, folder 70-72
    - The New School for Social Research, 1966, 1968-1969, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 924)
    - The New Seabury Press
      See: box 22, folder 561
    - New Statesman, 1963, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 925)
    - New World Resettlement Fund for Spanish Refugees, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 926)
    - The New York City G.I. Coffehouse Project, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 927)
    - New York Civil Liberties Union, 1961-1965, 1968, 1972, undated (Box 36, Folder 928)
      See also: box 5, folder 73 box 36, folder 928
    - New York Herald Tribune
      See: box 60, folder 1400
    - New York Post, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 929)
    - New York Public Library
      See: box 124, folder 662
    - The New York Review of Books, 1964, 1966, 1968, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 930)
      See also: box 15, folder 378 box 48, folder 1166
    - The New York Times, 1948, 1958-1960, 1963, 1965-1968, 1970, 1973, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 931)
      See also: box 55, folder 1322 box 129, folder 704
    - The New York Times Book Review, 1949-1950, 1952-1953, 1960, 1963, 1967, 1971-1972, undated (Box 36, Folder 932)
      See also: box 54, folder 1312
    - The New Yorker, 1950-1951, 1954, 1957-1958, 1960, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 933)
      See also: box 33, folder 829 box 47,folder 1148-1149
    - The New Yorker staff, 1958, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 934)
    - Newsday, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 935)
    - Newsweek, 1964-1965, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 936)
    - Newton, David R.(*), 1945-1948 (Box 37, Folder 937)
      See also: box 60, folder 1414
    - Nicholas, John S., 1958 (Box 37, Folder 938)
    - Nicolson, Benedict, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 939)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1945, 1953, undated (Box 37, Folder 940)
      See also: box 9, folder 211 box 48, folder 1171
    - Nies, Judith, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 941)
    - Nims, John Frederick
    - Niven, Frederick, 1924 (Box 37, Folder 942)
    - Nivola, Costantino, 1959, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 943)
    - Nobile, Philip
      See: box 12, folder 273 box 21, folder 531
    - Nomad, Max, 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 944)
    - Norden, Heinz, 1948-1949 (Box 37, Folder 945)
    - Norman, Gertrude, 1951-1954, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 946)
    - Norris, Frank Callan, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 947)
    - The Northwest Organizer, 1939 (Box 37, Folder 948)
    - Noyes, Eliot (includes D. Macdonald's statement for 1964 Aspen Design Conference), 1963-1964 (Box 37, Folder 949)
    - Oa - On (Box 38, Folder 950)
    - Oak, Liston M., 1945, 1950 (Box 38, Folder 951)
    - Oberlin, Russell
      See: box 86, folder 294
    - O'Brien, Justin(*), [1924-1928?], 1949, 1951-1952, 1959-1960, 1964, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 952)
    - Ocampo, Victoria
      See: box 105, folder 485
    - O'Connor, William Van, 1946, 1948-1950, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 953)
    - O'Hearn, Peter, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 954)
    - Olds, Elizabeth
      See: box 130, folder 712
    - Omar Khayyam Club, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 955)
    - Opie, Everett, 1973 (Box 38, Folder 956)
    - Or - Oz (Box 38, Folder 957)
    - Orlansky, Harold(*), 1943-[1946?]-1949, 1952, undated (Box 38, Folder 958)
    - Orwell, George(*), 1942-1949 (Box 38, Folder 959)
    - Orwell, Sonia (Mrs. George), 1956, 1958, 1960, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 959)
    - Osborn, Elodie (Mrs. Robert C.), 1953, 1955, 1960, 967, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 960)
    - Osborn, Paul, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 961)
    - Osborn, Robert C.(*), 1957, 1959-1960, 1962, 1964, 1967-1968, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 962)
    - Osmond, Humphrey, 1959 (Box 38, Folder 963)
    - Outlook, 1948 (Box 38, Folder 964)
    - Oxford University Press, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 965)
    - P.E.N.
      See: box 14, folder 362 box 18, folder 436
    - Pa - Ped (Box 38, Folder 966)
    - Pacifica Foundation, 1954 (Box 38, Folder 967)
    - Pacifica Views, 1945 (Box 38, Folder 968)
      See also: box 18, folder 448
    - Padmore, George, 1942, 1946-1947 (Box 38, Folder 969)
    - Paechter, Henry M., 1944-1949, 1951, 1956 (Box 38, Folder 970)
    - Palmer, George Anthony
    - Pannekoek, Anton(*), 1945-1947, 1949 (Box 38, Folder 971)
    - Pantheon Books(*), 1946, 1953-1954, 1959, 1962, 1970, 1972, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 972)
    - Paolera, Felix della(*), 1960-1961 (Box 38, Folder 973)
    - Paolucci, Henry
      See: box 9, folder 202
    - Parmelee, Maurice
      See: box 34, folder 855
    - Partisan Review, [1938?], 1942, 1944, 1946, 1964-1965, 1967, 1973, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 974)
      See also: box 10, folder 229 box 40, folder 989-990 box 42, folder 1030
    - Partito Commista Internazionalista, 1946 (Box 39, Folder 975)
    - Patchen, Kenneth, 1940-1941, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 976)
    - Pearce, Charles A., 1942, 1946 (Box 39, Folder 977)
    - Peck, James, 1946, 1960, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 978)
      See also: box 61, folder 1423
    - Peck, Seymour, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 979)
    - Pee - Ph (Box 39, Folder 980)
    - Pee, Mario
      See: box 90, folder 333
    - Pemberton, John de J., Jr.
    - Pradalés, Pierre, 1943 (Box 39, Folder 981)
    - Perkins, Dexter
      See: box 144, folder 61
    - Perkins, Frances, 1947 (Box 39, Folder 982)
    - Perkoff, Ann, 1948 (Box 39, Folder 983)
    - Perkoff, Stuart Z.(*), 1948-1950 (Box 39, Folder 983)
    - Persky, Daniel, 1954, 1956, 1958-1960 (Box 39, Folder 984)
    - Petersen, William(*), 1939-1940, [1943?]-1948, 1961 (Box 39, Folder 985)
      See also: box 49, folder 1184
    - Petrov, Vladimir N., 1948 (Box 39, Folder 986)
    - Philip Morris & Co.
      See: box 117, folder 591-595 box 117, folder 596
    - Phillips, Elizabeth, 1972-1973 (Box 39, Folder 987)
    - Phillips, Sidney, 1954-1955 (Box 39, Folder 988)
    - Phillips, William(*), 1937-1938,[1943?], 1948-1950, 1953, 1958-1962, 1963-1964, 1966, 1969, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 989-990)
    - The Phillips Exeter Academy(*), 1924-1926, 1928-1929, 1946-1947, 1951-1955, 1957-1958, 1961, 1962-1963, 1966-1968, 1970-1971 (Box 40, Folder 991)
      See also box 25, folder 663 box 60, folder 407 box 14, folder 53
    - Pi - P1 (Box 40, Folder 993)
    - Pilat, Oliver, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 994)
    - Pivert, Marceau(*), 1940-1944 (Box 40, Folder 995)
      See also box 9, folder 211 box 13, folder 330 box 27, folder 715 box 9, folder 212
    - Plastrick, Stanley
      See: box 12, folder 267 box 13, folder 339
    - Playboy, 1963, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 996)
    - Plimpton, George